Jonathan Lazarini

Customer Experience Lead at Wipro Digital

lazarini.jonathan@gmail.com

Summary

jonathanlazarini.com

Creating user experience, user friendly products according to user (end-users as well as executives, stakeholders) perception and behaviour.

Digital and Mobility. Services cross industries

UCD (ISO 13407) & Usability (ISO 9241 Usability)

- - - -

More details about my previous projects at: jonathanlazarini.com

Skills & Expertise

User Experience

Usability Testing

User-centered Design

User Interface Design

Agile Methodologies

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Scrum

Front-end Development

Adobe Creative Suite

Online Research

Quantitative Research

Qualitative Research

Human-computer Interaction

Interaction Design

Information Architecture

Usability

Bootstrap

W3C Accessibility

Tablets

Prototype

Adobe Edge

Photoshop

Cognitive Psychology

Axure

Illustrator

Storyboarding

Accessibility

Heuristic Evaluation

Mobile Devices

Persona

Cognitive Science

Automotive

ERP

CRM

Oil & Gas

Retail

Retail Banking

Banking

Financial Services

Telecommunications

Mobile Applications

iOS

Android

Customer Experience

JIRA

Visual Studio

TFS

Certifications

CSM (Scrum Master)

Scrum Alliance Licence #000433659 juin 2015

Agile Practitioner

Skills Matter juin 2015

Ergonomist - HCI & HFE

Université d'Aix-Marseille décembre 2008

Psychologist

Université d'Aix-Marseille septembre 2008

CSS Cross-Country

Code School Licence 40

Front-end Formations

Code School

Journey Into Mobile

Code School

Adventures in Web Animations

Code School

Assembling Sass

Code School

Fundamentals of Design

Code School

Blasting Off With Bootstrap

Code School

JavaScript Best Practices

Code School

ES2015: The Shape of JavaScript to Come

Code School

jQuery: The Return Flight

Code School

Staying Sharp With AngularJS

Code School

Real Time Web with Node.js

Code School

Building Blocks of Express.js

Code School

Warming Up With Ember.js

Code School

Anatomy of Backbone.js Part 2

Code School

Experience

Customer Experience Lead at Wipro Digital

septembre 2014 - Poste actuel (1 an 9 mois)

Leading digital transformation projects - Experience cross verticals.

Designing mobile (tablets, smartphones) native apps (iOS & Android) as well as hybrid apps and RWD approach.

Multichannel products (RWD) & Customer engineering:

- Delivery: UX strategy & Agile PM (Scrum/Kaban, CMS management
- User research: Usability testing, KPI tracking & Web analytics, Information architecture.
- UX Design: full interactive prototypes, style guide & branding.
- UI Design: Adobe CC, Photoshop, Illustrator, Muse, InDesign, HTML/CSS
- Interaction Design: Axure, Sketch, Origami, Edge Animate.
- RWD front-end development POC using HTML5 & CSS3 Bootstrap framework.

UX Specialist at Accenture

août 2013 - novembre 2014 (1 an 4 mois)

Senior UX consultant cross industries involved in global project for diamond clients - Mobility & Digital

UX Business development for Accenture – Managing junior UX designers – Mobility & digital department - UCD approach & UX team lead during projects.

Clients include main telecom company in Belgium (Brussels), top 5 oil & gas companies, sustainability companies.

Design mobile (tablets, smartphones) native apps (iOS & Android) as well as hybrid apps and RWD appriach.

- User research: Usability testing, KPI tracking & Web analytics, UX strategy & Agile PM
- UX Design: full interactive prototype, style guide & branding.
- UI design: Photoshop & illustrator
- RWD front-end development POC using html5 & css3 Bootstrap framework

UI / UX Designer at MidlandHR

avril 2012 - août 2013 (1 an 5 mois)

Defining UX strategy of the company including:

- Research
- Design
- Evaluation

Applying UCD principles for designing HR solutions (ERP).

Core UX Agile processes

Gathering requirements from Users, Stakeholders & BA: Interviews, Brainstorming, Focus groups, Reporting to executives

Design: Information Architecture, Sketches, Blueprints, Prototyping, Visual design, UAT

Human Computer Interaction researcher - Contractor at Renault

juillet 2011 - avril 2012 (10 mois)

Integrating on-board systems fitted with touchscreens (7' & 9') for vehicle ranges from 15k to 40k €

Scope statements:

- UI Requirements
- Storyboarding/Wireframes (Ps, Ai)
- Flowcharts / User journeys (Ms Visio)
- Information Architecture
- Design workshops
- Planning/Reporting meetings

UX Consultant at Yuseo

novembre 2010 - juillet 2011 (9 mois)

France, Paris – IT project management support

UX consultancy company providing optimizations within digital channel.

User experience design, Information Architecture

Scope statements:

- Quantitative studies (online card sorting & IA)
- Qualitative studies (user testing, benchmarks)
- Designing: Wireframes, Visual design
- Project management (Off pre-sales): Defining protocols and user testing campaigns (more than 80 users), screeners, recruitment, e-mailing campaigns & reporting

Personal experience and assessment:

• Mastering UX – IT project management support

Junior UX Researcher - Temporary at Laboratoire d'Observation des Usages des TIC

mars 2010 - novembre 2010 (9 mois)

France, Rennes – R&D

Multidisciplinary public company related performing ergonomics studies. Research and development projects on New Information and Communication Technologies. Eye-tracking, Surveys, User tests, Benchmarks.

Main responsibilities:

• European E-learning project (Serious Game – budget of 1.5 M €)

User Centred Design: Users requirements – Surveys – Questionnaires – Ergonomics benchmarks – User test – Eye tracking – Storyboarding (Powerpoint)

Personal experience and assessment:

• Mastering User Centred Design, Usability, IT Acceptability

UX Researcher - Temporary at Institut de Médecine Navale du Service de Santé des Armées

mai 2008 - décembre 2008 (8 mois)

Toulon, France - Defense

Navy. General hospital performing telemedecine (medical consultations) for operating expense militaries in French Guyana

Main responsibilities:

• Upgrading E-medicine software's usability for army medical doctors (collaborative application Lotus Notes – client side/front office)

UCD: User's requirements – Activity analysis and formalizing user's work flow; Heuristics evaluation (ergonomics criteria) - Mockups - Upgrading specifications and requirements.

Personal experience and assessment:

• Team work with programming teams and physicians

UX Researcher Intern at Universite de Provence Aix Marseille I

décembre 2007 - mai 2008 (6 mois)

Aix en Provence, France – R&D/Design

PHD University. CAD software project with european partneers. Designing front end interfaces of the software for professional designers.

Main responsibilities:

• Working for a PhD project on CAD software "TRENDS" – Ergonomics program

UCD: User's requirements and functionalities specifications with programming team Heuristics evaluation (HCI Expertise) and Wireframes/Storyboards

Human Factor Engineer Intern at Institut National de Recherche sur les Transports et leur Sécurité février 2007 - juin 2007 (5 mois)

Salon de Pce, France – Transport

Multidisciplinary platerform working on driving process.

Reports and recommendations for road safety

Main responsibilities:

• Performing interviews with drivers.

Designing experimental protocols with human factor engineers teams to be applied on a simulator.

Courses

Master, Ergonomics, Human Computer Interaction

Université de Provence (Aix-Marseille I) Human Factor Engineering

User Experience

Cognitive Sciences

Human Computer Interaction

Languages

French

(Bilingue ou langue natale)

English Italian

Spanish

(Capacité professionnelle complète) (Compétence professionnelle limitée)

(Notions)

Education

Université de Provence (Aix-Marseille I)

Master, Ergonomics, Human Computer Interaction, 2006 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Ergo IHM

Université de Provence (Aix-Marseille I)

Licence, Sciences cognitives - spécialité Ergonomie, 2003 - 2006

La cordeille

Literature

Interests

User Experience, UX, UCD, IxD, UX, IA, Usability, Design, UI, Ai, Axure, Scrum, Agile, Usability Testing, Prototyping, Snowboarding, Football

Organizations

Scrum Alliance

Agile practitioner - CSM

Test Scores

CSM - Scrum Alliance

juin 2015 Résultat :97%

Projects

R Link

July 2011 to Present

Membres: Jonathan Lazarini

Shift by wire

July 2011 to Present

Membres: Jonathan Lazarini

Planete Vesta

March 2010 to Present

Membres: Jonathan Lazarini

Volunteer Experience

Eco Volunteering at TCV

juin 2014 - Poste actuel

http://www.tcv.org.uk/volunteering

Jonathan Lazarini

Customer Experience Lead at Wipro Digital

lazarini.jonathan@gmail.com



4 people have recommended Jonathan

"Jonathan was one of the first UX specialists that I ever employed and oh boy, that was a great decision. We worked together for just over a year and during that time he introduce me, my Business Analysts and my Developers to the rigors and excitement of creating some great UX. When Jonathan left, we of course had some great UX, but we also had a formal structure in place to create more. Jonathan helped with the selection of tooling and was really great around the creation and adoption of style guides to help get product consistency and branding sorted. When you have a blank canvas it's a huge challenge to create version 1. Passion plays a huge role here – and it was down to Jonathan's passion for UX that got us well on the road to having a great product look and feel. Jonathan, when it comes to UX, your a safe pair of UX hands and a joy to work with."

— **Dr Leslie Bowie**, managed Jonathan indirectly at MidlandHR

"It was a great pleasure to work with Johathan, he is very passionate about usability and improving the systems he works on. He's sharp, detailed and adaptable. I wouldn't hesitate to work with Jonathan again."

— Michal Paternoga, worked with Jonathan at Renault

"Jonathan was a real pleasure to work with. He demonstrated the highest level of User centered expertise and knowledge I have seen in a UX specialist. Jonathan is able to see both the big picture when it comes to global interaction concept, whilst also being able to drill down into the details. His other main quality is certainly his ability to tackle complex project combining self-sufficiency and team spirit."

— Nicolas Ringot, managed Jonathan at Renault

"Jonathan was always willing to offer the best services and had an excellent rapport with clients, co-workers, employers, and other professional organisations. He brought up his UX expertise on many projects he worked on. Jonathan is attached to details and he would be an asset to any employer. I recommend him for any endeavour he chooses to. I would not hesitate to work with him again."

— Samy KEFI, worked directly with Jonathan at Yuseo

Contact Jonathan on LinkedIn